# Ran Ding

Senior Software Developer (.Net Full Stack - Fulltime)

Suwanee, GA

kevinding0218@gmail.com 678-761-5501

github.com/kevinding0218

## **SUMMARY**

Accomplished, Creative and enthusiastic software developer with 7+ years of experience excels in every stage of the life cycle of software development, including UI/UX design, coding, debugging, testing, and deployment. With a get-it-done, on-time spirit, and years of experience implementing and adapting technically sophisticated online web applications.

Currently I'm specialized in responsive web application such as Angular 7 with .NET Core in Microservice Architecture with Docker, also I am participating with Azure and Mobile Programming.

- Adept at overseeing all phases of software development lifecycle, from design and documentation to implementation.
- Exceptional experience working in fast-paced, deadline-oriented environments.
- Strong team leader with extensive background managing and training junior employees.
- Ability to quickly learn new concepts and technologies. and analyze Complex Technical Information.

## **SKILLS**

- Programming Language: C#/Typescript/Javascript/Java/VB/Python, etc.
- Frontend: Angular 7/VueJs/RxJs/Ngrx/GraphQL, JQuery/Ajax/Bootstrap/Html5/Css/Scss, Nativescript/Ionic, Json/Xaml/Razor, etc.
- Backend: Asp.Net Core Web API/Web Form/SignalR/.Net MVC/Node.js/NestJS, Entity Framework Core/Serilog/Ado.net/Linq/OData/Polly/RabbitMQ/Serilog, Xamarin, etc.
- Database: MS Sql Server/MySQL/Redis/Azure Storage/Firebase/Mongo/Sqlite, etc.
- Other: Jira/Bitbucket/Git/TFS/Github/Azure App Service, Npm/Nuget/Webpack/AngularCLI, Sql Profiler/Redgate/Postman/Crystal Report, SSIS/SSRS Reporting Service, IIS, etc.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Senior Software Developer (.Net Full Stack - Fulltime)

McKesson Corporation, Atlanta, GA

Jul 2018 – Current

- Lead and build new enterprise level SPA from scratch by using Angular 7/Rxjs/Ngrx/GraphQL, Bootstrap and JQuery as front end, design new real-time data chart in websocket.
- Lead and build new enterprise level Restful Services in .Net Core Web API with EntityFramework Core(Database-first) in multiply layer with DI pattern, implement middleware components such as Logging, Global Error Handler and JWT Auth, etc.
- Research and leverage current service architecture into DDD-oriented microservices with docker container and message-broker.
- Participated in Azure application Service Fabric in cloud programming with Redis and Azure Storage.
- Collaborate with developers, QA, product owner and scrum master to understand prioritize needs and produce high quality software changes.
- Key technologies: C#/.Net Core Web API/Entity Framework
   Core/SignalR/OData/Polly/RabbitMQ/Serilog, Angular
   7/Rxjs/Ngrx/GraphQL/WebSocket/Bootstrap/Html5/JQuery, SQL Server 2017/Azure DB/Redis,
   Jira/Bitbucket/Git/TFS, dockerhub etc

## Software Developer (.Net Full Stack - Fulltime)

McKesson Corporation, Atlanta, GA

Oct 2015 - Jun 2018

- Act as full stack developer for delivering enterprice level Asp.Net SaaS web application to healthcare
  entities by involving in Agile and scrum development process.
- Lead and build responsive design MVVM forms from scratch by using Vue, Bootstrap, javascript/jQuery, etc. The ability to learn, analysis and integrate third party API/tool quickly.
- Develop Restful Service in Web API 2 in .Net 4.5, maintain and enrich the legacy Asp.net webform app, C# backend data integration application with Ado.Net to improve for the internal portal to view the status of services, schedulers and monitors.
- Work on high-volume, large-scale(>5TB) databases with writing complex store procedure, optimizing data access and improving database performance.
- Knowledgeable in Healthcare (340B program)/EDI transform business workflow.
- Key technologies: C#/.Net 4.5/.Net Web API/Ado.Net, Vue/Bootstrap/Html5, SQL Server 2017, Jira/Bitbucket/Git/TFS etc

## Software Engineer(.Net and Java - Fulltime)

Ravello Insurance Technology, Sandy Springs, GA

May 2013 - Sep 2015

- Developed enterprise level Claims/Policy/Billing web applications by using ASP.NET(Webform)/Java(Spring) for leading insurance provider.
- Upgraded legacy application by integrating AngularJS(1.2) and Bootstrap 2 with JQuery/Ajax to SPA.
- Drove continual improvement to system architecture by refactoring old legacy code. Fix and improve the compatibility issue between different browsers.
- Troubleshot and resolved bugs all over frontend/backend/sql server to ensure optimized product environment.
- Key technologies: C#/VB/Asp.Net Webform/.Net MVC 3/Spring MVC/AngularJS/Bootstrap/Javascript/JQuery/Ajax/SQL Server 2008R2

## **Software Developer(.Net Silverlight - Volunteer)**

Leap American LLC, Mason, OH

Sep 2012 - May 2013

- Design and build user-friendly music recommendation web application by using C#/.net Silverlight 5.
- Worked in Ado.Net to manage data model and schema, writing store procedure to implement the data transaction from database level.
- Worked closely with the Lead Developer and Architecture to ensure architectural integrity and product quality.
- Key Technologies: C#/.Net Silverlight 5/XAML/IIS 7.5/Javascript/JQuery/AJAX, .Net music player

#### C++ Developer(QT - Intern)

Guodian Nanjing Automation Co., Ltd., Nanjing, Jiangsu, China

Feb 2010 – Aug 2010

- Implemented using C++/QT and compile among multiple types of operating systems to develop a realtime communication embedded system.
- Collaborated with the team well and capable of handling complicated social relationship.
- Worked closely with Lead engineer to ensure product quality and documentation.

## **EDUCATION**

## Master of Science (M.S) / Computer Science

University of Dayton, Dayton, OH

# Bachelor of Science (B.S) / Computer Software Engineering

Nanjing University, Nanjing, Jiangsu, China 2006 - 2010

## **EVENTS AND AWARD**

- NgAtlanta 2019 Conference and Workshop
- Employee of the Month

Macro Helix IT Department Aug 2016

- Employee of the Month

Macro Helix IT Department Feb 2016